{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. In a common emitter transistor the current gain β equals to _______, where have their usual meanings.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Ib/Ic",
        "b": "Ie/Ic",
        "c": "Ic/Ib",
        "d": "Ic/Ie"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. In a transistor, the ______________ is moderately doped and largest in size.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "emitter",
        "b": "base",
        "c": "Junction",
        "d": "collector"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. In a transistor the _________ is of moderate size and heavily doped.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "emitter",
        "b": "base",
        "c": "Junction",
        "d": "collector"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. When the transistor is used in the cut-off or saturation state, it acts as?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "An amplifier",
        "b": "Zener diode",
        "c": "A switch",
        "d": "An AND gate"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. When a transistor is used in common emitter configuration, the __________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "output is between the base and the emitter",
        "b": "input is between the base and the emitter",
		"c": "input is between the collector and the emitter",
        "d": "output is between the base and the collector"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. In order to use the transistor as an amplifier, it has to operate in the ________ region.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Switched region",
        "b": "Cutoff region",
        "c": "Active region",
        "d": "Saturation region"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. For a transistor, β = 100. The value of α is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1.01",
        "b": "0.99",
        "c": "100",
        "d": "0.01"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. If α-current gain of a transistor is 0.98. What is the value of β-current gain of the transistor?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.49",
        "b": "49",
        "c": "4.9",
        "d": "5"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },    
	
	{
      "question": "9. The emitter-base junction of a transistor is ______ biased while the collector-base junction is _____biased.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "reverse,forward",
        "b": "reverse,reverse",
        "c": "forward,forward",
        "d": "forward,reverse"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. The emitter of a transistor is ________________ doped.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "of moderate size and lightly",
        "b": "of moderate size and heavily",
        "c": "very thin and heavily",
        "d": "very thin and lightly"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}
